我們要穿越意大利的葡萄園
We're taking a four-week bicycle trip
完成一次為期四周的自行車旅行
through the vineyards of Italy!
我們認為今年夏天 海莉 迪蘭
We figure that this summer, our whole lives
還有他們的雙胞胎寶寶搬進來以后
are gonna be turned upside-down
我們的生活會被攪得天翻地覆
when Haley, Dylan, and their twins move in with us,
所以干嘛不度個"外孫月"放松一下呢
so why not splurge on a grandbaby-moon?
因此我們一直在聽語言學習帶
So we've been hitting the language tapes,
騎固定腳踏車
the, uh -- the stationary bikes,
而且我還一天對克萊爾吹好幾次流氓哨
and a couple of times a day, I wolfishly whistle at Claire
讓她為羅馬人的經典熱情做好準備
to prepare her for that timeless Roman charm.
我不敢相信我們在弗里特利餐館
I can't believe after all those nights at Fratelli's
聊了那么多次要去意大利之后
talking about going to Italy,
我們真的要去了
it's actually happening.
美國夫人
Ohh, American lady!
為什么你要這么對我
Why do you do this to me?
別再逼我對你練習扇耳光了
Don't make me practice my slap on you again. Mm.
怎么了
What's that?
我在等電話 我為咱們的周年紀念
Oh, I'm on hold. I'm booking us
給咱倆預定了托斯卡納的一座
into a converted castle in Tuscany
-翻新城堡 -它有護城河嗎
- for our anniversary. - Does it have a moat?
我一直在處理我們所有的稅單
I've been working on all of our receipts for taxes.
我們很可能得到一筆退款
Looks like we're getting a refund,
那就意味著我們能夠負擔得起...
which means that we can afford to --
讓小矮人放下護城河上的吊橋
To pay the dwarf who will lower the drawbridge
只要我們能夠回答出他的三個謎語
if we answer his riddles three?
讓我先斷了你的念想 沒有護城河
I'm gonna nip this in the bud. No moat.
這趟旅行真是個好主意
This trip was such a great idea.
我知道
Oh, I know.
今年夏天這兒會一直忙忙碌碌的
Things are gonna be so hectic here this summer.
好詭異 一想到有人稱呼我們為外公
It's weird to think people will be calling us
-和... -別說 千萬別說
- Grandpa and -- - No, please don't say it.
別說那個詞 它讓我覺得自己好老
Don't say that word. It makes me feel so old.
但我想過讓他們叫我什么了
But I have thought about what I want them to call me.
-阿嬤 -阿嬤
- Gammy. - Gammy.
行 我們試試這詞怎么樣
Well, let's take her for a spin.
"大家注意 阿嬤來啦"
"Hey, everyone, Gammy's here!"
"抱歉 今天不行 阿嬤心情不好"
"Sorry, guys, not today, Gammy's in a mood."
不錯啊 這詞行
Yeah, it does. It works. Mm. Yeah.
-嗨 室友們 -嗨..."室友"
- Hey, roomies. - Hey -- "Roomies"?
拿這些箱子和袋子做什么
What is with all the boxes and the bags?
我知道我們說會等寶寶出生再搬進來
Well, I know we said we'd move in when the babies come,
但是后來我們想到早搬來早省錢
but then we thought about all the money we'd save.
許許多多錢[西語]
Mucho dinero.
-好 -你看起來很生氣
- Yes. - You look mad.
我應該先告訴你的 我很害怕跟你說
I should've told you. I was afraid to tell you.
因為如果你不樂意 我怕自己應付不來
I didn't think that I could handle the disappointment
隨之而來的失望
if you weren't happy about it.
但你沒有不開心吧 對嗎
But you're not unhappy about it, right?
-是吧 -親愛的 親愛的
- Right?! - Oh, honey. Oh, honey.
我的天 你最好了 我太愛你了
Oh, my gosh, you're the best. I love you so much.
好一趟高潮迭起的情緒之旅啊
Wow! What a journey.
等我荷爾蒙開始作亂了 生活會是什么樣啊
What is my life gonna be like when I'm in the hormonal stage?
等一下 還有一件事情
Oh, wait, there was one more thing, um...
我該把這些箱子放在哪兒
Hey, where should I put these boxes?
我媽突然來了
My mom surprised us. We were hoping
我們希望她能暫住幾天
she could stay a couple days.
你們好 你們好
Hello, hello!
我們也是時候該正式見面了
Well, it's about time we officially met,
考慮到我們的基因已經在海莉的子宮里
considering our DNA is already swirling around
難舍難分了
in Haley's womb.
菲爾
Phil.
你好
Oh, hey.
-克萊爾 -你好
- Claire. - Oh, hi.
-我是法拉 -你好 法拉
- I'm Farrah. - Hi, Farrah.
-你看起來好眼熟 -我在抗議活動中
- You look so familiar. - Well, I meet a lot of people
認識了很多人
with my work in the protest movement.
你參加過"象牙就是謀殺"樂跑活動嗎
Oh, did you participate in the Ivory is Murder Fun Run?
-沒印象 -親愛的 不如你帶法拉
- Not that I recall. - Sweetheart, why don't you show Farrah
-看看她要睡在哪里吧 -不用了
- where she will be sleeping. - Oh, no,
我只需要兩個承重鉤子
I just need two weight-bearing hooks
間隔七英尺就行了
spaced seven feet apart.
這件和服可以變成吊床
This kimono converts to a hammock.
-準備就緒[意語] -意大利
- Pronto! - Italy!
-他們回復了 我手機呢 -糟糕糟糕
- They answered! Where's the phone? - Oh! Oh, no, no, no.
-手機去哪兒了 -找到了 這兒呢
- Where's the phone? - I got it, right here.
找到了嗎 我接住了
You got it? Get it.
兄弟 我很抱歉
Oh! Oh, buddy, I'm so sorry.
-我給你拿點冰塊 -該死
- Let me get you some ice. - Damn it!
別擔心 我帶了磁石
No, no, don't worry. I brought magnets.
她就這么處理頭部受傷嗎
Is that the way she treats all head injuries?
這讓我有了個理論
Because I've got a theory.
我想把這些舊玩具送給海莉的寶寶們
I want to give these old toys to Haley's babies.
喬 你太有心了
Oh, Joe, that's so sweet!
現在我的壁柜里有地方放蜥蜴了
Now I have room in the closet for my lizard.
蜥蜴 我以為你們只是去寵物店
Lizard? I thought that you were just
看一下而已
going to the pet shop to look.
我沒法對那張小臉說不
I can't say no to that face.
你得在他青春期前一直唱紅臉了
You're gonna have to be bad cop 'til puberty,
等到普里契特的喉結
you know, when the Pritchett Adam's apple
和小胡茬冒出來的時候
and fuzz-stache show up.
曼尼 你也應該給雙胞胎點東西
Manny, you should also give something for the twins.
你們都要當舅舅了
You both are gonna be uncles.
這在我們家是項光榮的傳統
That's a very proud tradition in our family.
說得沒錯 喬 我們的先祖阿爾瓦羅
That's right, Joe. Our great-great Uncle Alvaro
是位有名的南美解放斗士
was a famous South American freedom fighter.
你開玩笑嗎 我的先祖伊拉茲馬斯
You're kidding? My Great Uncle Erasmus
是阿拉莫戰爭中的英雄
was a hero at the Alamo.
我們再多說幾句就會發現
We're four sentences away from realizing
他們互相殘殺了吧
they killed each other, right?
喬 下周你要打扮成英雄
Joe, next week, you have to go
去學校
to school dressed as a hero.
為什么不打扮成先祖阿爾瓦羅呢
Why don't you dress as Uncle Alvaro?
還是先祖伊拉茲馬斯好
Or Uncle Erasmus.
杰 好傻好天真
Ay, Jay, that's cute,
阿爾瓦羅可不只是個戰爭英雄
but Alvaro was not only a war hero.
他還是有名的斗牛士
He was a celebrated matador,
弗里達·卡羅[天才女畫家]的探戈導師
Frida Kahlo's tango instructor,
波哥大先驅報小漫畫比賽的
two-time winner of the Bogota Herald
兩屆冠軍
cartoon caption contest.
沒有冒犯的意思 不過我覺得他連給
No disrespect, but I don't think he was fit to shine
伊拉茲馬斯·杰·普里契特擦鞋都不配
Erasmus J. Pritchett's boots,
那鞋還是他跟戴維·克羅克特掰手腕的時候
which, incidentally, were made by a 9-foot Texas diamondback
他一腳跺死的一條近三米長的響尾蛇做成的
he stomped to death while arm-wrestling Davy Crockett.
他的衣服都是殺動物做成的嗎
Did he kill all his clothes?
是啊 來上樓 我給你看看
He sure did. Come upstairs. I'll show you.
我留著一個他的戒指 里面有顆牙
I got a ring of his with a tooth in it
是他從美洲獅嘴里打下來的
he punched out of a puma.
杰總是這樣
Jay does this all the time.
他不尊重我們家族 吹噓自己的
He disrespects our heritage and inflates his own.
我一點都不相信什么先祖伊拉茲馬斯的故事
I mean, I'm not buying this Uncle Erasmus guy at all.
我建議我們探究一下
I say we do a little digging.
好 我們可以像托爾圖加偵探一樣
Yes! We can be like Inspector Tortuga,
先祖阿爾瓦多大受歡迎的兒童書里的
the turtle detective in Uncle Alvaro's
那個烏龜偵探
popular children's book.
他總是慢慢地偵破罪案
He was always very slowly solving crimes.
杰的先祖1830年左右確實住在德克薩斯
Turns out Jay's Uncle Erasmus did live in Texas in the 1830s,
但是關于他的描寫不多
but not much was written about him.
-格雷琴 -曼尼爾
- Gretchen. - Manuel.
再一次 我非常抱歉
Again, I'm so sorry abou--
這些書你必須兩周內還回來
You'll have to return these within two weeks.
不像我的電話 你過了兩周都不回
Unlike my phone calls!
臭小子
Senor.
我們必須深入挖掘 既然歷史
We had to dig deeper, and since history
是由勝利者書寫的
is written by the victors...
非常感謝
Muchas gracias.
我帶了自己的
I brought my own.
墨西哥的資料對他在阿拉莫戰役中
Mexican sources had a bit more to say
真實的表現描寫得更多一點
about his actual involvement in the Alamo.
-好了 -真的嗎
- Okay. - Oh, really?
你要把我給女兒買的第一件古馳衛衣
You want to give away the very first Gucci hoodie
-送人嗎 -行了 就是因為買了那么多貴衣服
- I ever bought our daughter? - Okay, "First Gucci"
退休規劃師才不給我們當顧問了
is why our retirement planner fired us as clients.
而且 海莉和迪倫的孩子是雙胞胎
Also, Haley and Dylan are having twins, okay?
-他們真的需要這些東西 -我知道
- They really need this stuff. - I know.
我還是不能相信她懷孕了
I-I-I still can't believe she's pregnant.
-不過 -我知道你要說什么賤話了
- Although... - I know you're about to say something catty.
你都要射出賤氣了
You're practically purring.
克萊爾二十幾歲的時候不是也"挺會玩"嗎
Wasn't Claire a bit "fun" on her 20s?
你知道 我們老家有句俗話
You know, we have a saying back home --
"有其母必有其女"
"The crawdad don't skitter far from its crick."
你手里拿著名牌衣服
Okay, you're clutching a Dolce & Gabbana onesie.
你到底想當都市人還是鄉下人
Decide who you are.
再說了 你們家也有
And, by the way, it's not like your family
一個惹事生非的家伙 好嗎
doesn't have a wayward streak, okay?
小帕可沒多可靠
Pam's not exactly responsible.
不好意思 一個不可靠的女人
Oh, I'm sorry. Could an irresponsible woman
能在監獄獲得"最有進步摔跤手"的獎嗎
win her prison's "Most Improved Wrestler" Award?
行了 我們就承認
Okay, let's just admit
兩家都有狂野不羈的女人吧
we have wild women on both sides of the family.
天啊 可能莉莉身上
Oh, God. Maybe it's good
沒有那些基因是件好事
Lily wasn't saddled with those genes.
她肯定沒有 就算有什么
She sure wasn't. If anything,
我擔心的也是她這么大了還有點幼稚
I'm worried she acts a little young for her age.
我是說 她都十一歲了 長大到不適合
I mean, isn't 11 a little too old
玩這些獨角獸和泰迪熊玩具了...
for these unicorns and teddy bears and --
天 《花花女郎》
My... Playgirl?
天啊
Oh! Oh, God.
她從哪搞到這東西的
Where -- Where did she get that?
我都不知道這雜志還在出版
I didn't even know they still made these.
現在知道印刷媒體沒有消亡還挺欣慰的
Although it's heartening print media isn't completely dead.
你跑題了
Okay, you're getting off track.
我們的女兒在看裸男
Our daughter is looking at naked men.
我知道 我們得跟她聊聊這件事
I know. We're gonna have to talk to her about it.
你知道嗎 我的父母從來不跟我
You know, my parents never talked to me
談及性的話題
about anything sexual.
他們只是在馬交配的時候
They just sent me to the stables
讓我去馬廄看著
when the horses were breeding,
這可讓我有了些不切實際的"期待"
and wow, did that create some unreasonable expectations.
不會吧 誰告訴她的
No way! Who told her that?
她...
She -- Uh-oh.
老爹們表情怪怪的 過夜的時候見
The dads have their faces on. See you at the sleepover.
好呀
Hey!
是這樣的 我們想跟你談個事
So, listen, we need to talk to you about something.
我們...
We, uh -- We found a --
在你房間里找到一本雜志
a magazine in your room.
這沒什么好尷尬的
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
老天 一點都不丟臉 你...
Oh, God, no, not at all. You're -- You're going through
你正經歷激動人心的轉變時期
a very exciting period of -- of change
-荷爾蒙也在釋放 -也開始有沖動
- and -- and hormones. - And -- And -- And, um, urges.
知道了 你們真會教孩子
Got it. Solid parenting.
-明天見 -不不不不不
- See you tomorrow. - No, no, no, no, no, no.
-別走 -親愛的 坐下
- No, no, no. - Sweetheart. Come on.
我知道聊這個讓你很不自在 但是
I-I-I know this is uncomfortable, but...
你不應該為對性好奇
You shouldn't be ashamed about wondering
而感到羞愧
or being curious about sex.
肢體交纏
You know, the mingling of bodies
也可以是表達愛的美好方式
can be a beautiful expression of love.
別說了 學校里也有關于這個話題的課
Stop! They have classes about this in school,
如果你們不希望我看那種雜志
and if you don't want me looking at magazines like that,
就不要放在沙發上
don't leave them on the sofa!
沙發 怎么...
The sofa? How did --
-怎么會跑到沙發上 -我不知道
- How did it get on the sofa? - I don't know.
我不... 是保姆
I don't -- Ah, the babysitter.
又或是海莉 或者小帕 也可能是克萊爾
Or, you know, Haley, or -- or Pam, or Claire.
我們剛剛還在聊她們幾個有多變態
We were just talking about how perverted they are.
等一下 這是1997年的雜志
Wait a minute. This is from 1997.
封面是大衛·杜楚尼
And David Duchovny's on the cover.
你以前不是喜歡大衛·杜楚尼嗎
Didn't you have a thing for David Duchovny?
什么 我都不知道那是誰
Why -- Wha-- I don't even know who that is.
他就是演那個俗套的科幻劇的
He was on the -- you know, the cheesy sci-fi show,
叫什么來著 《X檔案》之類的
the, uh -- What was it? "The X-Files" or something?
就是弱智版的《黑衣人》
You know, kind of a dumbed-down "Men in Black"?
劇里面有個經典句子
They had that saying, you know?
好像是 "真相...就在上面"
Saying was, "The truth is... up there"?
你明知道是"真相就在外面"
You know damn well it's "The truth is out there"!
你別弄皺了
Don't -- Don't you crinkle it.
你為什么有一本20年前的裸男雜志
Why do you have a 20-year-old nudie mag?
穆德探員對我意義重大 好嗎
Agent Mulder meant a lot to me, okay?
他那么帥 總是眉頭深鎖
He was brooding and handsome
還迷戀一個雖然焦躁但性感的紅毛
and obsessed with an uptight yet sexy redhead.
你猜怎么著 你根本沒機會
Yeah, well, guess what. You wouldn't have had a chance
泡到大衛·杜楚尼 因為你看
with David Duchovny because, look.
他最不喜歡的就是"不誠實的人"
One of his turn-offs is "Dishonest people."
而且你為什么把雜志隨便亂丟
And why is it just lying around the house?
我前幾天把垃圾桶
I was bringing the trash bins
拉回車庫時
into the garage the other day,
注意到我的一箱舊物
and I noticed an old box of my stuff.
我覺得很懷念 于是決定翻看一下
I got nostalgic, and I decided to flip through it.
-等等 垃圾日 就是上周三嗎 -對
- Wait, garbage day? L-Last Wednesday? - Yeah.
就是我們開了那瓶梅洛干紅
The day we opened the bottle of Merlot,
拿進臥室喝
took it back to the bedroom,
然后有了"超乎尋常的體驗"的那晚嗎
and had a rather spectacular... session?
-是那晚嗎 -你少來
- Uh, was it that night? - Oh, please,
那是多年來你第一次不是因為鄙視
it was the first time in years I'd seen your eyes
而[爽到]翻白眼
roll back in your head without irony.
我深受你吸引 真是不好意思啊
Well, excuse me if I am attracted to you.
但不只是因為我 對嗎
Except it wasn't just me, was it?
那晚床上有三個人
There were three of us in that bed.
我第二天還送了你一打紅玫瑰
I sent you a dozen roses the next day.
原來我應該送其中六朵給大衛·杜楚尼啊
Apparently, I should've sent six to David Duchovny.
要不要這樣
Oh, come on!
我看完性感美男圖
So what? I got a little extra worked up
比平時更性奮點 有什么大不了
after looking at a sexy picture.
這是很普遍的事
People do it all the time.
胡嬌說這是他買"猛男"牌紙巾的唯一理由
Pepper said it's the only reason he buys Brawny paper towels.
那我想在情感層面上只與你一人產生共鳴
So, I guess I'm weird for wanting to purely connect
是我奇葩
with you on an emotional level.
算了 我去健身房了
Know what? I'm going to the gym.
好消息 大衛·杜楚尼
And good news, David Duchovny.
你今晚不會孤單一人在沙發上了
You're not gonna be alone on the sofa tonight.
請你把iPod遞給我好嗎
Can you please hand me my iPod?
你已經剝奪了我的尊嚴
You've robbed me of my dignity.
不能把我霸氣的離場也奪走
You will not also rob me of my glorious exit.
謝謝
Thank you!
好了 哥們
There you go, buddy.
現在你看起來像個真正的英雄了
Now you look like a real hero.
我想我應該不能帶刀去學校
I don't think I'm allowed to bring a knife to school.
刀一點都不鋒利[機靈]啦
It's not sharp at all.
顯然你也不機靈
And neither, apparently, are you.
我說了吧 如果我們等幾分鐘
I told you if we waited a few minutes
他就會幫我們鋪好梗
he'd give us a delicious segue.
你的先祖伊拉茲馬斯·普利契特
Your uncle Erasmus Pritchett
在阿拉莫之戰中是英雄沒錯
was a hero at the Alamo...
不過是敵軍那邊的
but for the other side.
沒錯 交戰時他躲在衣柜里
Yeah, he hid in a closet during the fighting,
然后偷了一條裙子
then stole a dress and escaped
假扮成妓女逃走了
by pretending to be a prostitute.
什么 我不相信你說的
What?! I don't believe you.
這些是官方教會文獻
These are official church documents.
這一段說到他用軍方機密
In this part, it says that he traded military secrets
交換朗姆酒和新胸衣
for rum and a new corset.
"至今 在新拉雷多 '伊拉茲馬斯'
"To this day, in Nuevo Laredo, 'to Erasmus'
仍代表'趴在地上哭'的意思"
means 'to cry facedown on the ground.'"
這有一張他諂媚的照片
There's a picture of him cringing.
我不敢相信我給我的蜥蜴取名伊拉茲馬斯
I can't believe I named my lizard Erasmus.
那是戰時 喬
It was wartime, Joe!
他遭受了地獄般的經歷 我們不能因此鄙視他
We can't judge a man who has lived through that kind of hell.
他戰后一直在
He spent his post-war years
散布素食主義的福音
spreading the gospel of vegetarianism.
我沒這個先祖
I have no uncle.
這種順勢治療藥
Oh. This homeopathic remedy
一定能改善海莉的孕吐
is really gonna help Haley with morning sickness.
我坐優步時
Uh-huh. I got the recipe from a doula
遇到的助產師給我了這個偏方
I met in an Uber pool.
你有一件事是對的
Well, you were right about one thing.
的確聞起來像
It does -- It does smell like
被閃電擊中的水牛
a buffalo that was struck by lightning.
你什么時候回俄勒岡啊
When -- When are you heading back up to Oregon?
我在那兒待夠了
Oh, I'm done with that place.
世上最老套的故事
Oldest story in the world.
我以為我找到了一個好人 但一天早上
You know, I thought I found a nice guy, then one morning,
他說他找到了六個新女人
he up and tells me he's found six new women.
我受夠那些奧修大師了
Mm. I'm done with Bhagwans.
以迪蘭媽媽的身份重返人間
Coming back as Dylan's mother?
不好玩 媽媽
Not funny, Mom.
一點都不好玩
Not funny at all!
老兄 你真的沒事嗎
Buddy, are you sure you're okay?
相信我 我是個護士
Trust me, I'm a nurse.
如果我有腦"真"蕩 現在就會有明顯癥狀
By now there'd be clear signs if I had a concursion.
天 你媽看起來好眼熟
Gosh, your mom looks familiar.
她之前做過一陣模特
She used to do a little modeling.
她最近照片還被人盜用去
Recently, she had her likeness stolen
"脂肪冷卻手術"的廣告牌上
for one of those "Freeze-the-Fat" Billboards.
迪蘭的媽媽是
Dylan's Mom was the hot chick
《性感小野貓》音樂視頻里的辣妹
in the "Sex Kitty" music video.
? 性感小野貓 ?
♪ Sex kitty ♪
♪ Sexy kitty ♪
? 性感小野貓 ?
♪ Sex kitty ♪
? 性 ?
♪ Se-- ♪
歌寫得不怎么樣
The songwriting isn't perfect,
但這個視頻讓歌起死回生
but this video changed everything.
? 性感小野貓 性... ?
♪ Sex kitty, se-- ♪
那倆自行車不住那吧
Those bikes don't live there, do they?
因為那是擺放生產浴缸的絕佳位置
'Cause that is an ideal north-facing spot
剛好面朝北
for a birthing tub.
我不知道海莉
I wasn't aware that Haley
考慮在家生孩子
was considering a home birth.
我本來沒打算 但法拉讓我看清了
Oh, I wasn't, but then Farrah really opened up my eyes
生產工業的丑陋面目
to the birth-industrial complex.
這個房間有點在散發出
You know, this room is kind of vibrating
古老傷痕的感覺
with ancient wounds.
-我們用驅邪鼠尾草熏一下 -好的
- Let's sage the area. - Okay.
迪蘭 親愛的 你能拿個電風扇
Dylan, honey, do you think you could grab that fan
吹散下廚房的怪味嗎
and maybe de-funk the kitchen a little?
天啊
Oh, my God.
迪蘭的媽媽是不是很眼熟
Is, uh -- Is Dylan's mom at all familiar to you?
是的 謝天謝地你也注意到了
Yes! Thank God you noticed it, too.
我不敢相信這將會成為我們生活的常態
I can't believe that is gonna be in our life on a regular basis.
我知道 她快要把我弄瘋了
I know. She's been driving me kind of crazy
自我小時候開始
since I was a kid.
你知道有多少個夜晚我在床上
Do you know how many nights I went to bed
用枕頭捂著嘴大叫她的名字嗎
screaming her name into a pillow?
繼續說
Go on.
-她弄壞了 -不 是你弄壞了
- She broke it! - No, you broke it!
姑娘們 沒關系 另外 你們是誰
Girls, it's fine! Also, who are you?
我每月得帶一次我的繼女
Oh, I get my stepdaughters once a month
我前妻要在國民警衛隊輪班
when my ex-wife's on rotation with the National Guard.
孩子們 小心南美栗鼠 好嗎
Mm. Girls, be careful with the chinchilla, okay?
你們知道他很容易被嚇得屁滾尿流
You know he has a nervous bowel.
-姑娘們 -阿嬤
- Hi, girls! - Gammy!
阿嬤
Gammy?
姑娘們叫你阿嬤嗎
The girls call you Gammy?
有意思了 因為我也希望
That's funny, because I was hoping
海莉的雙胞胎將來
when Haley's twins came along,
這么叫我
they might call me that.
那恐怕會容易弄混
Oh, well, that might be confusing.
但你可以被叫做其他啊
But maybe you could be something else.
-嬤嬤怎么樣 -或許我們現在
- How about "Gaga"? - Maybe we don't have to lock
還不用確定任何叫法下來
anything down right now.
天啊 我喜歡
Oh, my God. I love it!
你好啊 嬤嬤
Hey, Gaga!
小鼠跑了 抓住他
Squeaker's loose! Get him!
我來
I'll get him!
-你看到了嗎 菲爾 -什么
- Do you see it, Phil? - What?!
沒 我什么也沒看到
No, I didn't see anything, so...
對不起 小迪
I'm so sorry, D!
如果你不是我的偶像
If you weren't my hero,
我要懷疑你是故意的了
I'd wonder if you're doing this on purpose!
天啊 爸爸
Oh, my God, Dad!
他怎么回事啊 媽
What's wrong with him, Mom?
-媽 -克萊爾
- Mom? - Claire?
嬤嬤
Gaga?
帥哥 這個座位有人嗎
Hey, handsome, this seat taken?
你來這干嘛
Hey, what are you doing here?
我給你帶了奶昔 但...
Well, I brought you a smoothie, although,
你不需要 因為你已經是
you don't need it because you're already
百分百的美味果繽紛了
100% fruity deliciousness.
或許我該直奔主題
Maybe I just get right to it.
米奇爾 我很感激你的心意...
Look, Mitchell, I appreciate what you're doing --
不 聽我說
No, no, listen.
莉莉今晚去朋友家過夜
Lily's at a sleepover tonight,
所以我在耳語度假水療中心定了套房
so I got us a suite at Whispers Resort and Spa.
就是珍妮弗·安妮斯頓離婚后
Isn't that the place, uh, Jen Aniston goes to
-去的那家嗎 -是的
- after her divorces? - Yes.
《花花女郎》的事我很抱歉
And I'm sorry about the silly Playgirl thing.
我想讓你體驗我每天所體驗的感覺
I-I want you to feel what I feel every day.
就是你眼里除了我沒有別人
That you only have eyes for me.
你可以說我傳統 我就是心里容不下別的男人
Call me old-fashioned. I just don't see other men.
親愛的 你的心率高到警報響了
Sweetie, your-your heart rate's setting off an alarm.
你還是先別騎車了
Why-why don't you get off that bike?
是啊 好主意 不如這樣
Yeah, that's a good idea. You know what?
我們先去水療 看能不能提前開始項目
Why don't we go to the spa, see if we can get an early treatment?
我喜歡
I love that.
奶昔
Oh, smoothie.
好的
Okay.
你真的出了好多汗
Hey, you're-you're really sweating.
你該拿條毛巾擦擦了
You should get a towel.
你表現得好奇怪
Okay, you're acting weird.
-到底怎么回事 -好吧 我只是
- What's going on? - Okay, look, I just --
因為酒店很興奮
Um, I'm excited about that hotel.
那里發生過好多好萊塢名人名事
I mean, there's a lot of Hollywood history there.
傳聞
You know, they say
《小淘氣》那幫演員常在那搞群交
the Little Rascals used to have orgies there.
小卡
Hey, Cam!
我差點忘了你給我們做的自制蛋白棒
I almost forgot the homemade protein bars you brought for us!
下次見
Well, I'll see you next time!
好 這人誰啊
Yeah! Who is that?
這片風光可真有意思
Wow, that's an interesting view.
哪有意思了 停車場而已
What? It's a parking lot.
-那有個垃圾桶 -拜托 少來了
- There's a Dumpster. - Oh, please. Come on.
你選這輛單車是為了能在前排
You picked this bike so you could have a front-row seat
觀摩這場猛男...
to this little peep sho-
我的天
Oh! Oh, my God.
我們那晚"超乎尋常的體驗"
That night of our "Spectacular session,"
正好是你從健身房回家后
you had just come from the gym.
真好奇你那天勁頭為什么那么足
Well, I-I wonder what got your engine so revved up, huh?
真相就在外面
The truth is out there!
你知道嗎
Okay, you know what?
我很容易動搖 行了吧
I'm weak, okay?
真不敢相信你因為我看雜志而羞辱我
I can't believe you shamed me for looking at a magazine
而你一直在給這群猛男
when you've been baking protein bars
-做蛋白棒 -或許就是這個原因
- for Thunder from Down Under! - Maybe that's why.
這讓我很內疚
It's because I-I felt guilty about this.
不必內疚 明白嗎
Well, don't, okay?
我們可以去看其他男人
We are allowed to look at other men
不必覺得內疚
without feeling guilty about it.
要是這樣能激發你 大可去看
And-and if it inspires you, then go for it,
因為歸根結底
because at the end of the day,
好處都是我享用了
I'm the one who gets to reap the rewards.
這話沒錯 好吧 我很抱歉
That's true. Okay. Look, I'm sorry.
我們快離開這吧
Let's just get out of here.
這就走 好吧
Oh, now? Okay.
或許我該加入這間健身房
Maybe I should join this gym.
不行 繼續看你的懷舊裸男雜志去
No, stick to your vintage nudie mags.
這里是我的
This is mine.
-他叫什么 -查克
- What's his name? - Chuck.
查克
Oh, Chuck.
喬 太可愛了
Oh, Joe, so adorable,
你看起來像幼年版阿爾瓦羅先祖
you look like a little Uncle Alvaro!
最后的點睛之筆 懷表
One last touch -- the pocket watch,
永遠停在3點30分
permanently broken at 3:30
因為它擋住了善妒的弗洛倫斯·南丁格爾
after it stopped a bullet shot by a very drunk
酒醉后射出的子彈
and jealous Florence Nightingale.
或許我是酸葡萄心理
Maybe it was sour grapes,
但我開始覺得這家伙是個騙子
but this guy was starting to sound like baloney.
我很確定假如我用盡一切手段
I was sure that if I left no stone unturned,
最終 某天
eventually, one day,
我會找到先祖阿爾瓦羅的丑聞
I'd find some dirt on Great Uncle Alvaro.
我就知道
I knew it!
西蒙·弗朗西斯科·阿爾瓦羅
Simón Francisco Alvaro
輾轉于不同小鎮 勾引有錢寡婦
would go from town to town, seducing wealthy widows
編造自己在戰爭中的勇敢故事騙她們
with made-up stories of his bravery in battle.
把她們的所有錢財都浪費在喝酒賭博上
After frittering away their fortunes on drink and dice,
然后換下一目標 只給他的受害人
he would move on, leaving his victims with nothing
留下一枝紅玫瑰
but a single red rose
和梅毒
and syphilis.
有人想聽歷史小課堂嗎
Who's up for a little history lesson?
-看起來 -等一下
- It seems -- - Wait, wait, wait, wait.
再演一次
Do it again.
哥倫比亞的肩頭
The yoke of Spanish oppression
將不會再套上西班牙壓迫的韁繩
will chafe Colombian shoulders no longer!
我的佩劍在渴求歐洲人的鮮血
My saber thirsts for European blood!
-太可愛了 -好極了
- So cute! - Bravo!
他自己查到背下來的
He looked it up and memorized it himself.
爸 你知道那些孩子
Hey, Dad. You know how kids tease me
總笑我是班上最矮的嗎
'cause I'm the shortest kid in the class?
可別聽他們說的那些鬼話
Oh, don't listen to what they say!
沒錯 先祖阿爾瓦羅只有一米五
Right! Uncle Alvaro was only five feet tall
可是他領導了一整支軍隊
and he led a whole army!
我要像他一樣勇敢
I'm gonna be brave like him.
先祖阿爾瓦羅萬歲
Viva Uncle Alvaro.
我享受了很多年以我先祖為榮的日子
I enjoyed a lot of years taking pride in my great uncle.
我不想奪走喬在這方面的機會
I didn't want to rob Joe of that.
忍著不說真的很不容易
It wasn't easy biting my tongue,
但我向家族里另一個偉大的先人學習
but I took a page from another heroic relative --
他就是魯拉赫·麥普里契特
Lulach McPritchett --
勇敢驕傲的蘇格蘭勇士 被英國佬所捕獲
proud Scottish warrior, captured by the English,
用盡世上各種手段刑求逼供
tortured for months using every method imaginable,
但他還是沒有透漏任何一點秘密
and never once giving up a single secret.
別去查他
Don't look him up.
夫人[意語] 為何如此難過
Signora, why so sad?
讓我看看你如通心粉般的大微笑好嗎
Let me see that big macaroni smile, ah?
你怎么找到我在這
How did you find me?
安東尼奧打電話來說
Antonio called and said
你點了一杯燃燒森布卡茴香酒...
you'd ordered a flaming Sambuca...
但一口沒喝 只靜靜看它燃燒
...and just watched it burn.
一切都發展得太快了
It's all just going too fast.
五個月前
Five months ago,
海莉剛跟迪蘭復合
Haley got back together with Dylan.
然后我媽媽去世 再接著海莉就懷孕了
Then my mom dies. Then Haley's pregnant.
后來還發現是雙胞胎
Then it's twins.
接下來"搬過來暫住一個夏天"變成了
Then, "Come move in with us this summer" turns into
"叮咚 為您帶來雙胞胎提前體驗包
"Ding-dong, we're here with an early preview of twins
與一只大小便失控的南美栗鼠
and an incontinent chinchilla,
而且呢 比《猛鬼街》殺人魔佛萊迪
and, in the most terrifying return since Freddy Krueger
重返榆樹街大開殺戒還可怕的是
sashayed his way back onto Elm Street,
我媽媽轉世附身在了法拉的身體上"
my mother reincarnated into the body of Farrah."
你... 你怎么能對這一切都如此淡定
How -- How are you handling this all so well?
誰說我淡定了
Who says I am?
我不得不離開家里
I had to get out of there,
不然我要害海莉成為單親媽媽了
or I was gonna make Haley a single mom.
我連傷了迪蘭兩次
I hit Dylan again, Claire.
-但你不是有意的啊 -能確定嗎
- But not on purpose. - Are we sure?
你是說你心里可能暗藏怨念
You mean, like, you might have some buried anger
記恨他偷走了你的寶貝閨女嗎
towards him stealing away your baby girl?
我真希望你是故意的
Oh, I so want it to be on purpose.
我自己一個人在瘋人島上好孤獨啊
Gets lonely out here on crazy island.
沒事啦
Oh, well,
我們好歹還有意大利嘛
we still have Italy.
真的有嗎
Do we?
聽我說 我上網查過了雙胞胎
Listen, I've been doing some research on twins,
它們容易像我們的女兒當年那樣
and it seems that, like our daughter, they --
提早出生
they tend to come early.
但哪怕只有10%的幾率
Even if it's a 1-in-10 chance,
我也不想到時候海莉身邊唯一的母性角色
I can't risk having the only maternal figure present
是那個浴缸生產的妖女
be that tub-birthing Wiccan.
我得在她身邊陪她
I got to be there for Haley.
的確是很壓力山大
It's overwhelming for sure,
但我們許許多多的美好回憶
but haven't a ton of our best memories
不都是從一家人的各種混亂中產生的嗎
come from the anarchy of our house?
比如盧克把腦袋卡在欄桿中
Like when Luke got his head stuck in the banister?
哪一次被卡住
Which time?
或是艾麗克斯的科學展覽設計
Or when -- when Alex's science fair project
害整個鄰里各家各戶都停電了
blacked out the whole neighborhood
而且還是在超級碗期間
during the Super Bowl?
還有
Or when, uh,
海莉想從盧克的窗戶溜進家
Haley snuck in Luke's window
-結果那周我們才剛給盧克買了彈弓 -天啊
- the same week we bought him a slingshot? - Oh, God.
真的是...
That was... Mm.
我們家是有點像瘋人之家
So, it's a-a madhouse,
但換另一個角度想
but on the other hand,
這個家馬上就要迎接幾個新的寶寶了
we're gonna have a couple babies in the house,
他們會是海莉與迪蘭的寶寶
and they'll be Haley and Dylan's.
他們一定會鬧出很多笑料
So they'll be doing funny stuff.
所以...
So...
感覺我們還是會去旅行啦
looks like we are going on a trip?
-格雷琴 -曼尼爾
- Gretchen. - Manuel.
我對我們不歡而散感到抱歉
Look, I really am sorry about the way things ended --
為時已晚
That chapter is closed.
我們現在是單純的工作關系
We have a strictly business relationship now.
還喜歡這本書嗎 還是你的眼睛
Did you enjoy this book, or did you find your eyes
瞟向了更短小的猶太書籍[人]
drifting toward a shorter Jewish one?
聽我說 我跟肖莎娜已經結束了
Okay, Shoshana and I are over.
最傷心的就是當我發現
It was beyond hurtful that you found a woman
你另找的姑娘名字里還帶有兩個"噓"的音
whose name has two "shhh" sounds in it.
顯然你還在傷心
Clearly, you're still upset
而且看來也沒機會握手言和了
and there is no hope for reconciliation.
既然如此
So...
我想向你道別
I'll just say good-bye
并希望你會允許我在我們的愛歌中退場
and hope you'll allow me to play myself off with our song.